Anton Kastsenich

Krakow, Poland

Mobile: +48 530 670 758 anton.kostenich@hotmail.com Skype: antonkostenich

PERSONAL STATEMENT

A talented 5-years experienced software engineer with a strong technical background in the field of computer science. Participating in all stages of application development process from discussing requirements with customer to delivering completed product. Possessing a good team spirit, strong self-discipline and ability to organize and present complex solutions clearly and accurately.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer, EPAM, Poland, Krakow — September 2017 — present List of projects, I was involved in:

1. iOS helper application to manage your Internet connection, that provides ability to install modem and manage many settings, connect you with Wi-Free access points, and show user's mobile usage.

Responsibilities: implementing new features, estimating new functionality, bug fixing.

Technologise: Swift, iOS SDK, ReactiveSwift.

iOS developer, Itransition, Minsk, Belarus — November 2012 — August 2017 Took part in many iOS projects as a developer/team-leader. The most important are listed below:

1. iPad portfolio-like application for visual artists.

Responsibilities: implementing features, bug fixing, refactoring legacy code.

Technologies: Objective-C, iOS SDK, Core Data.

2. Evernote-based memory game for iOS-based devices.

Responsibilities: implementing features, bug fixing.

Technologies: Objective-C, iOS SDK, Evernote SDK.

3. Enterprise application for sharing documents and task management.

Responsibilities: architecture creation, communication with the customer, design and estimating new functionality, implementing features, code review, sharing experience.

Technologies: C#, Xamarin (MonoTouch).

4. Application for complex real-time baby monitoring system.

Responsibilities: implementing new features, communication with the customer, estimating new functionality, bug fixing.

Technologies: Objective-C, iOS SDK, Core Data.

5. Application for housing authority company and its processes. Responsibilities: architecture discussions, design/estimating/implementing new

features, bug fixing, code review. Technologies: C#, Xamarin (MonoTouch), MVVMCross.

6. Application that provides guides for weight loss and helps people to find success in nutritional care.

Responsibilities: team leading, architecture discussions, design/estimating/implementing new features, bug fixing, code review, integrating and improving development processes.

Technologies: Objective-C, iOS-SDK.

Teaching Assistant, BSUIR, Minsk — September 2015 — July 2017

Teaching students basics of CPU architecture and Assembly language, system programming (both Windows and Unix systems) and multi-threaded programming with C/C++, helping them with their term project. Integrating VCS into studying process (Git via Github), formalizing grading criteria and code quality metrics.

EDUCATION

1. Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics, Minsk Faculty of Computer Science and Networks — B.S. in Computer Science, July 2015 Fields of study: PC and CPU architecture, system programming, network programming, signal processing.

Main projects:

- 3D chess game written with C++ (DirectX);
- Windows malware for hiding files written with C++ (WDK);
- Ruby-like language interpreter (lex and yacc);
- Diploma project web-service for managing and auto-grading programming assignments written with Ruby on Rails and CoffeeScript (PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RabbitMQ).
- 2. Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics, Minsk Faculty of Computer Science and Networks M.S. in Computer Science, Jan. 2018 Fields of study: cloud computing, multiprocess and multithreaded systems, signal processing, artificial neural networks.

Main project:

— high-load and scalable Elixir based web system for analyzing and aggregating social networks data.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Knowledge of different programming languages: Objective-C, Swift, C#, C/C++, Ruby, Erlang/Elixir, Javascript.

Knowledge and understanding of mobile cross-platform development.

Knowledge of different programming paradigms: imperative, object-oriented, functional.

Experience in TDD and covering legacy code with tests.

Good knowledge of algorithms and data structures.

Good debugging and profiling skills.

Database experience: SQLite, PostgreSQL, MongoDB.